Yusuf Eko Anggoro

Back-End Developer

Jakarta | +62 859 3453 1182 | anggoroekoyusuf@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A back-end developer with 3+ years of experience building, developing, implementing **Test Driven Development**, and maintaining. I really enjoy learning new things, especially about the latest technology. My current back-end language is **PHP**, **JavaScript** and **Golang**.

EXPERIENCE

PT Telkom Indonesia – Jakarta, Indonesia

Back-End Developer (August 2019 - present)

- Building, developing, implementing Test Driven Development, analysis and maintaining
 microservices architecture such as gamification service, ticket service, notification service, user
 service and worker service. RESTful APIs or Apache Kafka function as the glue that integrates
 the microservices into application.
- Skill in reading technical documentation and back-end integration with third-parties.
- Utilitized **OpenShift** to configure and deploy applications.
- Worked on NoSQL and SQL databases like MongoDB and Oracle.
- Experience with container-based deployment using **Jenkins** and **Docker**.
- Used **Apache Kafka** for Publish/Subscribe pattern in applications dealing with messaging.
- Used GIT for version control.
- Experience in **Agile** Development process with Atlassian Jira.
- Implementing best practices.
- With caching (Redis), ELK stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana).
- Used MinIO for enterprise file storage.
- Used FCM for notifications.

Coding Bootcamp Arkademy - Jakarta, Indonesia

Full-Stack Developer (July 2019 - August 2019)

• Arkademy is a software engineering program that provides a 6 weeks hands-on coding curriculum that focuses on mobile development with react native and node JS.

EDUCATION

Indraprasta PGRI University (2020 - 2024)

Bachelor of Information Technology - Coming Soon

Vocational High School 24 Jakarta (2017 - 2019)

Learn and explore all the ways of software development including making software, maintenance, software development organization management and quality management. Not only that, I also learned computer software from making websites, applications and everything related programming by mastering the programming language.

CERTIFICATIONS

• Ekipa Indonesia Scrum Master 1

SKILLS

- **Programming Languages:** PHP, JavaScript, Golang
- Back-end Technologies: Express.js, Golang, Laravel
- Web Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, CSS, React, Typescript, Laravel, CodeIgniter
- **Development Tools (IDEs):** Visual Studio Code

• Version Control: GIT

• **RDBMS:** MySQL, Oracle

• **NoSQL**: MongoDB

• Platforms: Windows, Linux

• **Methodologies:** Agile and Waterfall Methodology

• **Build Tools:** Jenkins CI/CD